ROSS MACDONALD

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(609) 610-2877 • rmac2289@gmail.com Portfolio • GitHub • Linkedin

EXPERIENCE

<u>Jr. Software Development Engineer in Test</u> — Axos Bank August 2021 - Present

- Designed, wrote and implemented a Node.js API to collect testing data and metadata from the Testim automation framework, send it to an Elasticsearch cluster and visualize it on multiple dashboards with Kibana
- Wrote and executed automated regression tests while utilizing custom JavaScript scripts to add flexibility
- Gained experience working in different phases of the Software Development Lifecycle, from project requirements until delivery
- Participated in daily Scrum meetings, sprint plannings, and sprint retrospectives
- Implemented a suite of regression tests to ensure continued functionality of an internal wire transfer app responsible for transfers of millions of dollars each year
- Executed both manual and automated tests in multiple environments, including QA, UAT & Production
- Spearheaded the QA team's effort to automate previously manual test scripts by providing teammates with framework and JavaScript support via 1 on 1 instruction and providing written manuals
- Worked with developers to pinpoint a bug's root cause and work towards a solution

<u>Public Safety Dispatcher III</u> — City of Mountain View April 2019 - July 2021

<u>Student</u> — Bloc Web Development Program January 2020 - July 2020

- Learned industry best practices and practical software engineering standards.
- Deployed full-stack web applications from code design to production while collaborating with a senior web developer.

<u>Communications Dispatcher</u> — County of Marin March 2017 - April 2019

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented Software Engineer with a passion for implementing new tech effectively and finding new ways to extend utility of existing tech. Proficient writing automated regression tests and experienced in multiple software development frameworks and databases, including JS (ES6), React, Node.js, Express.js, Testim.io, PostgreSQL and mongoDB.

TECH

JavaScript	Node.js	css
HTML5	React	Express
GraphQL	Postgres	MongoDB
TypeScript	Jest / Mocha	JMeter
Elastic Search	Testim.io	Git / GitHub

GENERAL SKILLS

Full Stack Development	Automation & Manual Testing
Performance Testing	Azure DevOps
RESTful APIs	НТТР
Apollo Server	CI/CD Tools
Testing / QA	SQL / noSQL
Leadership	Communication
SDLC	Agile / Scrum

EDUCATION

BS, Arizona State University • 2016 Magna Cum Laude